<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Joker's InfoSec Articles]]></title>
  <link href="http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-29T09:42:35-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ivan "Joker"]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ivanjokerbr@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Land of the Rising Sun]]></title>
    <link href="http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/from-the-land-of-the-rising-sun/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-29T08:41:21-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/from-the-land-of-the-rising-sun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Right know I&rsquo;m working on developing a benchmark suite of vulnerable Android apps for the sake of code review and teaching secure codding. Well, the first thing of course is listing all possible pitfalls a programming might fall. Compiling this information from multiple sources, I have just jumble across a nice document on the subject. Is from the Japan Smartphone Security Association and was released this year. The website in all in Japanese, but hey, there this <a href="http://www.jssec.org/dl/android_securecoding_en.pdf">Secure Coding Guidebook</a>. Cool stuff. Check it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android MITM]]></title>
    <link href="http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/android-mitm/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-07T15:37:38-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/android-mitm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I read about <a href="http://www.cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2012-6636">CVE 2012-6636</a> two things came to my mind: what executable (javascript) code can we inject? and what can we do messing with the xml/json/html etc being transmitted. Thinking for a few minutes and a bigger question arouse: do developers validate their data? I mean, servers can be compromised, traffic intercepted, bugs of all sorts.</p>

<p>So I went on and spend some weeks on this issue. To do so, these are the necessary tools:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://developer.android.com/sdk/index.html">Android SDK</a> of course</li>
<li><a href="http://mitmproxy.org/">mitmproxy</a> for intercepting requests and responses</li>
<li><a href="http://code.google.com/p/android-apktool/">Apktool</a> for decompiling the apks</li>
<li><a href="http://github.com/egirault/googleplay-api.git">Google Play API</a>, which is not an official google api, for downloading some apps</li>
</ul>


<p>First of all, I was interested in Brazilian apps, codded and deployed by brazilian programmers &amp; firms. So, no facebook, whatapps etc.</p>

<p>mitmproxy is pretty cool, cause you can hook a Python script to process all request and responses. I wrote a starter script and placed it <a href="https://github.com/ivanjokerbr/Miscelanea">here</a>.</p>

<p>mitm attacks normally are employed for grabbing data from the user to the net. Some examples that I found grabbed plaintext passwords, cookies , etc. I was more into using mitmproxy&rsquo;s script engine to alter the response from the server, and watching if the app would complain.</p>

<p>What I have found out ? Not one app validates its data. They all assume that what is received is crystal clear. No bad guy in the middle. I have done three payload examples:</p>

<ul>
<li>blocking content and displaying a false &ldquo;update your app&rdquo; type of social scan for malware delivery</li>
<li>injecting javascript for the above CVE</li>
<li>changing links to bad guys website</li>
</ul>


<p>I gave a presentation of these findings in BSides last July. You can check the slides <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/ivanjokerbr/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Oh! Https of course. This is the only way to prevent data manipulation. But even for apps with sensitive data, http transfers are used, and thus, may be a pathway to compromise. So developers, watch out and carry more for your data.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/first-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-06T15:03:02-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://ivanjokerbr.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/first-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For this first entry, I have decided to talk about some old work I&rsquo;ve done. Namely, my PhD Thesis. Basically, I&rsquo;ve developed a PoC tool for doing static analysis of concurrent component based Java code , that could check for inconsistencies. To do so, a control flow graph of the Java statements, not bytecodes, was created. Then, all relevent API methods were linked and analysis. Most inconsistencies could be detected by analyzing the control flow between them.</p>

<p>If you are curious, check <a href="https://github.com/ivanjokerbr/Miscelanea/blob/master/ivanTheses.pdf?raw=true">here</a> for a copy of the text.</p>

<p>What can I conclude from my work ? 1) Static analysis is hard :&ndash;) 2) A lot of useful checks can be done statically. Regarding code review, these type of tools are a great allie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
